<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Mirella van Teulingen</title>
    <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Mirella van Teulingen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create SVG charts and animations without a JS Library</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/svg-charts-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/svg-charts-animations/</guid>
      <description>At Dreamsolution we need to visualize a lot of data using bar charts, pie charts, counters etc. Most of the time we use the Highcharts library for the charts. Now I had some use cases where a library as Highcharts is overdone. The question was how can I create a simple pie and bar chart without using a library (Highcharts, Greensock, Raphael, SnapSVG and SVG.js)?
Use case: pie chart, bar chart The designer already created a mockup how the bar and pie chart should look like, only thing I need to do is to make it work on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript for Frontend Developers</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/js_for_frontenddev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/js_for_frontenddev/</guid>
      <description> If you want to learn javascript, hopefully the list of resources below will help you to achieve your goals. Enjoy coding!
Books  PPK on Javascript DOM enlightenment Eloquent javascript A smarter way to learn javascript You don&amp;rsquo;t know javascript  Blogs  Quirksmode blog javascript.com Smashing magazine - javascript A List Apart - javascript   Other  Mozilla Developer - Event reference Mozilla Developer - CustomEvent Mozilla Developer - Ajax Mozilla - Developer Web Animations API PlainJS  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text, VSCode, Atom</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/sublime_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/sublime_part2/</guid>
      <description>Since 2013 I&amp;rsquo;m using SublimeText editor and wrote an how to about it to get you up and running. Now 5 years later I&amp;rsquo;m still using it. I&amp;rsquo;ve tested Atom and VSCode as well, but keep returning to SublimeText. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what packages I need for my environment and why I still like SublimeText over Atom or VSCode.
Sublime Text 3 is officially out since September 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minify javascript with GNU Make</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/make-minify-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/make-minify-js/</guid>
      <description>In my former blog post I wrote an introduction how to set up Makefile to generate CSS and minify CSS from Sass files. In this blog post I will extend the Makefile with a rule for generating minified javascript files.
My folder structure and Makefile looks like this:
FOO-project/ static/ css/ /* here comes the generated css files */ js/ base.src.js /* the minified js files will also be placed in this directory */ scss/ base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU Make for running tasks</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/make-taskrunner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/make-taskrunner/</guid>
      <description>Every front end developer have heard of or is using the task runners Grunt, Gulp, Broccoli. There are a lot of articles and how to&amp;rsquo;s on the web about these tools. However, there is one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get a lot of attention and that is GNU Make. It was originally created by Stuart Feldman in April 1976. GNU Make is not really popular among front end developers, it has a steep learning curve in comparison with Grunt or Gulp and there are not much examples on how to use it for front end development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use svg icons in Django templates?</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/svg-icons-django-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/svg-icons-django-template/</guid>
      <description>I am accustomed to use icon fonts in our projects at Dreamsolution, which are created with Fontcustom. It is a nice tool to generate the font icon from our own svg icons. Using the icon font in the last 3 years I always bump into some styling issues. The icon font has anti-alias and doesn&amp;rsquo;t get as sharp as vector images. The most annoying thing is positioning the icon next another element or text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A vanilla js and css tooltip</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/css-js-tooltip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/css-js-tooltip/</guid>
      <description>In february 2016 I was looking for a tooltip plugin which must fix 2 design issues: overflow:hidden and the window corners. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to need jQuery. During searching and testing a couple plugins, I thought, why not build one myself? It is a fun way to learn more about javascript and css animations.
In the same month I was also reading the book: this &amp;amp; Object prototypes, from the series You don&amp;rsquo;t know javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Font icons with Fontcustom and SASS</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/sass_fontcustom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/sass_fontcustom/</guid>
      <description>In 2013 and 2014 I used Icomoon to create font icons. It is a nice library and tool. You can choose icons from their library and they have the feature to upload your own svgs to create the font icon set. It is a great tool if you only need to generate the font icon once. But not when you have to add new ones to the set.  At Dreamsolution the company where I&amp;rsquo;m employed, the development and design goes in iterations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create clickable rating stars with only SASS and HTML</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/rating_stars_sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/rating_stars_sass/</guid>
      <description>In May, Roy Tomeij wrote the article &amp;ldquo;Configurable star rating without JS&amp;rdquo;. I was thinking how to do this using a font icon instead of a background image and make the stars clickable. I believe it would take less code to write, and it is. I had the code finished a couple of days later in May, but now I&amp;rsquo;ve finally have the time to post my solution. So here we go: HTML structure  I place the radio buttons in reversed order in the DOM to be able to do the hover + checked state in the right order with SASS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django form customization using Crispy Forms</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/customize_form_crispy_forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/customize_form_crispy_forms/</guid>
      <description>At Dreamsolution we regularly use Crispy Forms to generate complex forms in Django. I want to share some practical customization examples with Crispy Forms using the formhelper API. The examples are how to:  create Fieldsets wrap fields together insert HTML between fields  Create Fieldsets  In Crispy forms you can define a layout and structure the fields using the Fieldset layout object. However this means you have to add every field you want in the Fieldset layout object, and this can become a long list:  Layout( Fieldset( &#39;Your legend&#39;, &#39;first_name&#39;, &#39;last_name&#39;, &#39;street&#39;, &#39;house_number&#39;, &#39;addition&#39;, &#39;zip_code&#39;, &#39;city&#39; ) )    There is another way to create fieldsets and or manipulate the layout structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize Sublime text editor</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/customize_sublime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/customize_sublime/</guid>
      <description>Last year at the Fronteers conference in Amsterdam, Addy Osmani used Sublime Text Editor in his presentation. The editor looked really cool. Right after the conference I installed Sublime and looked around for packages which would make my life as front end developer easier and make editing more fun. After a month of playing with Sublime, I decided to leave TextMate (used it since 2005) and use Sublime as my new main editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Day 2013 Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/cssday_2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirellavanteulingen.nl/blog/cssday_2013/</guid>
      <description>Friday 14 june 2013 in Amsterdam I attended the CSSDay conference. Eight experts talked about 8 different CSS modules. The focus was on techniques of these modules we might not know about and the future of CSS. During the conference I learned that CSS is in very active development. It was an incredible, informative and awesome day. An high standard conference I&amp;rsquo;ve ever attended so far. I hope that there will be another one within 1 or 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>