<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conf_2012s on Mirella van Teulingen</title>
    <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conf_2012s on Mirella van Teulingen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I can smell your CMS</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/smellyourcms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/smellyourcms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Phil works as a web developer in London for R/GA. His presentation is to ask yourself and or your customer: do you really need a CMS? He also talks about the role of the web builder (agency) and the customer. It was a great and funny presentation. It really gave me energy and stuff to think about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The CMS Paradox&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Usually we give clients what they want, they want a system that is scalable and has lots of features. But the system which has to answer to these demands becomes very complex in the backbone but also for the user. Having a lot of features doesn&#39;t mean it is user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end the customer gets a system which can do a lot but the customer actually use only 20% of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should actually give what the customer really needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The responsibility of the agency/developer is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To learn by example: view the source.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Craft of code: to move forward as developers and agencies, respect the craft of code.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Example Grolsch.com has a 30MB homepage, just like Beetle.com with lots of scrolling effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CMS paradox is more obvious in large organisations. If you paid a fortune, then you&#39;ll sure it&#39;s a good system!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CMS paradox is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It doesn&#39;t really solve problems.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;it is enterprise level&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;expensive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;flexibility doesn&#39;t really give flexibility! It doesn&#39;t always end up in flexible solutions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Because you have so much choices -&amp;gt; paralysis&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;cost of system proportional to cost of changes: People need to get trained, the ability to make changes has a cost associated with it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Most content managers are ending up as a developer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has a powerful workflow. But does the shit get done?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People at the top like the idea of a controlling system, but the CMS is being used by an intern or a developer in the end, not the CEO. People tend to subvert the system because of all the security and controlling workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Code smell&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMS&#39;s don&#39;t just leave a smell, they actually stink!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Browse on the internet and just look at the url or code and you know that you&#39;re dealing with a CMS. Most CMS&#39;s expose the technology in URLs, such as an url ending in .php or .asp. This is a type of lock in. For example:&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eur.burton.com/on/demandware.store/Sites-Burton_EU-Site/default&#34;&gt;http://eur.burton.com/on/demandware.store/Sites-Burton_EU-Site/default&lt;/a&gt; That&#39;s not a cool URL :)&lt;br&gt;Or stinky code: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.episerver.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.episerver.com/&lt;/a&gt; pages has lots of crap in the HTML, like a hidden&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;lt;form&amp;gt;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;tag around everything that includes a hash of the view state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;URL design is a craft and should be part of the CMS when developing a website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;Challenge CMS stink. Fight for the chance to do good on the web.&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;- Phil Hawksworth&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Optimisation:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To serve a good performing web page you want a good base (not a CMS).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Building a site with modules kills performance and leads to a maintenance nightmare and makes Steve Souders cry.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modularity&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;flexibility (o really?): With all those modules you end up in a soup, maintenance is a nightmare. And kills performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;CMS: the power to ruin their site (Rachel Andrew)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Core feature: WYSIWIG = Danger. It ruins the layout of the site. We should protect the design experience. We should protect the markup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WYSYWIG can fuck up designs pretty often, and it&#39;s really hard to do it properly. Instead of WYSIWYG use Markdown. With Markdown you manage the content not the design. In that way, constrains can be enablers. When we are able to get the user to manage content and not design, it will keep the site future friendly and maintainable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;CMS enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Challenge the introduction of stink, simplify the implementation of the system. Build CMS more future friendly, like mobile support.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Challenge the customer by asking what content REALLY needs to be dynamic. Think about it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Consider NOCMS&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use for instance &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; it uses ruby to spit out static html. Or &lt;a href=&#34;http://grabaperch.com&#34;&gt;Perch CMS&lt;/a&gt;, which focuses on the front end, generating the admin part from the tagged front end design. Combine your website with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.varnish-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Varnish&lt;/a&gt; to speed it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source ain&#39;t free</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/os-aintfree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/os-aintfree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David DeSandro talked about his personal open source project and shared his experience, problems and solutions he run into when he shared his project with the world. The main subject of this presentation is how you can make money from open source projects. To get paid for the work you share with others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to do side projects you have to work on something that excites you. It is also a way to market yourself and to build and promote your personal brand. The community gets another tool for its toolkit. And most of these tools are free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The culture of free&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The culture of free, has the following components:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;you can view the source&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;there is no paywall&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;costs no money to...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;you can learn for free&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;use the resources&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;and market your stuff&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the ideal environment to be creative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It feels good to share your code with the world and you like it when others start using it. But there is a downside. People who use your code, they expect that you solve their problems to get your code working. For them it take 5 minutes to send the mail with a support question, but for you it take at least 30 minutes to help them. For David, these support questions were piling up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How do you deal with it?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;David asked himself &#34;Why don&#39;t I put a price on my product?&#34; Users have to make a value judgement, how much money is it worth for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are people who are making a money: like the app store, WP premium themes. Is there a market for front-end development resources?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FancyZoom was one of the first pioneers in this field. For $39 you could get a commercial license. David made Isotope as a commercial fill-in plug-in for Masonry with the FancyZoom model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David didn&#39;t like the available options:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;adopt fancyzoom license model.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;still open source = on github.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;github donation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Flattr&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Generic PayPal donation, but not happy with those donation options.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And started a company next to his agency for his side projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It feels kind a bit against the open source thought, but the results are incredible:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sold &lt;a href=&#34;http://isotope.metafizzy.co/&#34;&gt;Isotope&lt;/a&gt; for $37 / License (now $25), responsible for 25% of income in 2011.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Able to pay off car loan and student loan.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Impact on quality of life.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;At a cost of 20% of my free time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Also the price allows non technical users to contribute to the product.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are support emails bugging you? Think about it. If so, ask support fee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a huge market for commercial front-end dev resources. Free&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;open source ideal doesn&#39;t scale. It is OK to make money out of honest work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short notes</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/shortnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/shortnotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the talks I did&#39;t make much notes, are gathered on this page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;alexgraul&#34;&gt;Using JS to build bigger, better datavis to enlighten and elate&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;- Alex Graul - Twitter: @alexgraul - Video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/52851512&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/52851512&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex makes visualizations for the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He showed us a couple of examples to make data more interesting for the people, using animations and interaction. He is co-lead developer of the &lt;a href=&#34;misoproject.com/dataset/&#34;&gt;Miso project&lt;/a&gt;, this is an open source toolkit for creating interactive storytelling and data visualization of content. On the Miso project site you&#39;ll find some examples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mathiasbynens&#34;&gt;Ten things I didn&#39;t know about HTML&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;- Mathias Bynens - Twitter: @mathias - Video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/52851509&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/52851509&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mathias showed us some funny things he found out using HTML. For example he tried to use a name for setting a background color, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre rel=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;div bgcolor=&#34;fronteersconf&#34;&amp;gt; Fronteers Conf &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;returns the Fronteers yellow logo color. Or &#34;sick&#34; returns: #000c00. Try it for yourself to find out what your color is. It also gives different results when you remove the spaces in your name: bgcolor=&#34;your name&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mathias also advises not to be obsessive about HTML validation. It is build by people and also has bugs. But most of all, functionality is more important than validation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;Validation is a tool, not a goal.&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;- Mathias Bynens&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Characters don&#39;t need to be output escaped. The browser will render it OK, It is also DTD valid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also found out that &#34;font family&#34; does not need to be quote. It&#39;s rendered correctly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre rel=&#34;CSS&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
font-family: Comic Sans MS;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a font name beginning with a number does need quotes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;leaverou&#34;&gt;More CSS secrets: Another 10 things you may not know about CSS&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;- Lea Verou - Twitter: @leaverou - Video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/52882799&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/52882799&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lea showed us some awesome and powerful CSS(3) tricks. After this presentation you&#39;ll be longing for the day that these styles/animations are working cross browser, at least I do. It is amazing what you can accomplish with CSS, without using javascript. Although at the moment we still have to rely on one or the other untill it is available in the most common used browsers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presentation is really a must see. You can also check out the presentation of 2011 on: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/31719130&#34;&gt;vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;peternederlof&#34;&gt;Beyond simple transitions, with a pinch of JavaScript&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;- Peter Nederlof - @peterlof - Video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/53317255&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/53317255&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create animations we had to rely on custom javascript tools and libraries. We now can accomplish this with a simple CSS transition. However transitions still have their limits. Peter shows how to step beyond some of these limits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Benefits of CSS transitions&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;complete animation engine&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;no per-frame script calcuations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;optimized in every way!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should also use 3d transforms. It has no reflows. It is hardware accelerated, also on mobiles. It is battery friendly and widely supported. Except for IE, of course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there is a problem: transitions have no stop. You can&#39;t stop or interrupt an transition. Querying the CSS property values might not always work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The transitionEnd event is not fired when a transition is interrupted.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assigning styles via the javascript Api has a very high specifity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make fallbacks for critical cases: like left/top positioning for&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;IE8, instead of using transformations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use progressive enhancement.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;And most important, convince your client or project manager that this is OK.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rebeccamurphey&#34;&gt;JS Minty Fresh: Identifying and Eliminating Smells in Your Code Base&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;- Rebecca Murphey - Twitter: @rmurphey - Video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/53416986&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/53416986&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebecca talks about javascript code smell and how to solve this. It was a great talk with nice examples. I didn&#39;t even know that you can create html &#34;template&#34; and call it in javascript to make it more clean. That was a nice surpise. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/53416986&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; can tell you a lot more than these notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Code smells are a suggestion of a deeper problem&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The harm is that debugging is harder, maintainability suffers and features are hard to add. You never come back to fix it later. So create clean code from the start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The smell&lt;/strong&gt;: Repetitive code&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fix&lt;/strong&gt;: A function, object&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The smell&lt;/strong&gt;: complex functions&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fix&lt;/strong&gt;: More&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;smaller functions:keep functions short and simple and avoid complex if/else logic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The smell&lt;/strong&gt;: async acrobatics&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fix&lt;/strong&gt;: deferrers:manage and leverage asynchronicity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The smell&lt;/strong&gt;: html in javascript&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fix&lt;/strong&gt;: place it in the template. You can use _.template function from Underscore.js.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can download the presentation from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmurphey.com/js-minty-fresh/presentation&#34;&gt;Rebecca Murpheys website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;alexrussell&#34;&gt;What the legacy web is keeping from us&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;subtitle&#34;&gt;- Alex Russell - Video: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/53373706&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/53373706&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Progress is a man-made process, and like most man-made processes progress can be sped up and slowed down. Progress is good for people, for us. However it requires change and how many changes should be made and what changes should be made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;Accessibility is the most important thing! In the computing world.&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;- Alex Russell&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Progress delayed is progress denied! For example the canvas tag or rounded cornes, svg. Some took 6-8 years, while it was proposed in the beginning of 2000. Optimistically, new features shipped today will not be usable until 2016!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users do what they are asked to do. We can change that users start using new browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of HTML5 Video</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/statehtml5video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/statehtml5video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeroen Wijering shows how far JWPlayer is in using HTML5. There are some cool features. At the bottom of this article you find some links to demo&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;One thing i would never do again: charge a $15 license for YouTube :)&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;- Jeroen Wijering&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;JW Player:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Currently JWPlayer is used by over a million websites, including the White House.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;First sold to youtube in 1 year of existence.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;JW6 Player is the first version defaulting to HTML5&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why html5:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Apple iOS has no Flash support and Android is also stopping with supporting Flash.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ease of use for developers as easy as inserting an image.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Video as First class citizen:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Accessible for humans and robots,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Existing tools (css styling js scripting)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fast secure and stable (client&lt;a href=&#34;xsl:text&#34;&gt;xsl:text&lt;/a&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/xsl:text&#34;&gt;/xsl:text&lt;/a&gt;network)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Evolution&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First you had separate players, for example RealPlayer. Then you got Flash embedded players and now with HTML5 it is included. Over 80% of the world supports HTML5 video. 20% is IE8 and feature phones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gs.statcounter.com&#34;&gt;http://gs.statcounter.com&lt;/a&gt; use of HTML5&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;current state 80% of world supports html5 video&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MP4/web-m support is evenly split&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;MP4/h.264: most browsers + iOS and Android&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;web-m: Android, Firefox and Opera&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Firefox is going for MP4&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full screen Api:must-have video, except IE for the moment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chrome will replace h.254 for web-m&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What can you do with WebVVT?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;xsl:text&#34;&gt;xsl:text&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;track&amp;gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/xsl:text&#34;&gt;/xsl:text&lt;/a&gt;and webVTT are interesting innovations, available in Safari 6, Chrome 23 and IE 10. Code is free and usable:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can test the demo on: &lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.longtailvideo.com/track_demos/captions.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;xsl:text&#34;&gt;xsl:text&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;track&amp;gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/xsl:text&#34;&gt;/xsl:text&lt;/a&gt;demos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.longtailvideo.com/track_demos/chapters.html&#34;&gt;Chapter markers are available too in Chrome Canary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.longtailvideo.com/track_demos/descriptions.html&#34;&gt;Audio descriptions are available as well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.longtailvideo.com/track_demos/thumbs.html&#34;&gt;Preview thumbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.longtailvideo.com/track_demos/page.html&#34;&gt;Page interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.longtailvideo.com/track_demos/search.html&#34;&gt;Video search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pixel is not a pixel</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/pixelisnotapixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/pixelisnotapixel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a fast paced and interesting presentation. I&#39;ve learned a lot about pixels and where you can run into presenation issues on devices. I&#39;ve heard of Peter-Paul Koch but never seen or attended his presentations. It was a great experience and worth while!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have 3 kinds of pixels:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;css: like width:20px. Their size may be increased or decreased.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;device: The actual pixels on the screen. When the number of device pixels increases would break sites, so density-independent pixels were invented.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;densitiy independent&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Device pixels are the physical pixels on the the device. But they get higher and higher pixel densities, and the number of devic pixels increases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When building sites for different media/resolutions, ask your self this question: What kind of pixels am I using? CSS pixels related to javascript or device pixels when used in the code? In Javascript pixels might not be CSS pixels all the time. Usually it&#39;s CSS pixel, but sometimes it might be device pixels (dips) when related to screen size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is a viewport?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the total amount of space available for css layouts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On desktop it&#39;s equal to the browser window. An HTML element has an implicit width: 100% and spans the entire viewport.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Viewport for mobile&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The viewport for mobile is quite a bit more complicated. If the narrow browser window were to be the viewport, many sites would be squeezed to death. And mobile browsers must render all sites correctly even if they haven&#39;t been mobile optimized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;On Retina displays, device pixels are 640px, but device-independent pixels are still 320px to not break the Web on mobile&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;- @ppk&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;To work around this the mobile browser vendors split viewport in 2:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;layout viewport: css&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;visual viewport: actually what you use/see.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can compare it with looking through a keyhole. If you want to know how much of the website the user is actually seeing, use window.innerWidth (works on virtually all browsers except IE9 and Android 2.0)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;What does zooming do with the viewport?&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;on desktop the viewport stays the same, the css pixels become larger and less.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;mobile visual viewport becomes smaller but the layout viewport remains static, thus css declarations are not recomputed. The visual viewport now contains less css pixels.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Behavior of position:fixed&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you use/view position:fixed on the mobile? And what is fixed: the viewport. Ok, but which viewport? The layout viewport or the visual view?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It actually is browser dependent. There are differences in what browsers see as viewport:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Android, Chrome and Blackberry browsers use the visual viewport.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;IE9 the layout viewport.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Opera &#34;hops&#34;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;And safari does something weird.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;On layout viewport position: fixed behaves as absolute.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;On Opera the fixed hops up and down.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use these demo pages on your device/browsers to see the difference in behavior: &lt;a href=&#34;http://quirksmode.org/m/tests/positionfixed.html&#34;&gt;http://quirksmode.org/m/tests/positionfixed.html&lt;/a&gt; And &lt;a href=&#34;http://quirksmode.org/m/tests/devicefixed.html&#34;&gt;http://quirksmode.org/m/tests/devicefixed.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use the javascript:pageOffset, it works the same on mobile and desktop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Media queries and Meta viewport&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Media queries&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When using media queries, use width, and not device-width. Device-width is the width of your screen, that is not interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Width: Gives the width of the layout viewport and is in css pixels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Meta viewport&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meta name viewport tag tells the browser to set the size of the layout viewport. With this tag you can give a pixel value, or a device-width.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trick for responsive design: use the meta name viewport width=&#34;device-width&#34; and media queries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility on the web</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/accessibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to talk about accessibility? To invite people with a disability who wants to share how they experience the web. Instead of someone telling us what people with a disability need. I really find this the best way to learn how we can change things for the better. I liked the examples they gave as well. You see and understand their frustration when something isn&#39;t working on the web.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bor Verkroost&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bor is the founder and owner of 1-UP and 1-UP Consultancy. From birth, Bor has suffered from Dystrophic Epidermolysis Bullosa. A very rare and complex disease, leading to scarring and extreme vulnerability of the skin. Also, it immobilizes and causes the fingers to be severely contracted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He showd us 3 issues we should be aware of:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Touch related devices won&#39;t work for people with a hand disability.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drop down menu&#39;s with no delay are a pain.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Little space between navigation items are also troublesome.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bor explains that every touch related device won&#39;t work for people with a hand disability. He for instance works with a mouse and uses the search function to scroll. Scrolling 1 page designs are an issue for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also explains that when having a drop down menu, add a delay to the hover, so that the menu does not disappear the moment you move the mouse cursor from the menu. People have a hard time to focus their cursor on the right spot. This also means that enough space between navigation items is also valuable to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bram Duvigneau&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;Simplifying user interface will help in accessibility.&amp;rdquo; - Bram Duvigneau&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bram is a freelance software developer and accessibility consultant. Being blind from birth, he has a very practical vision on web accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bram showed Google search as an example: The voice over first goes through all the links which are placed in the top of the site, then the logo, search button etc. Before you finally get to the search results. When you have to rely on a voice over than it is very irritating when you have to go through non valuable information first, before you reach the section what worth hearing/reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bram also says that key controls are a problem too. Because as developer you can assign a key or combination to do something on the site. But how does a visitor knows which key is for what? This could be simpler, like using hot keys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;iPhone has an easy way to start the speaker and is more user friendly. Bram also explains that reading services are actually annoying for blind people. The reading option on a website is useless, because a blind person has his own software. Another thing I didn&#39;t know (because I don&#39;t work with Flash),is that Flash is not visible for VoiceOver on Mac, it is only useful with a screen reader on Windows. But the Narrator on Windows is useless until Windows 8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Another few examples&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest annoyances are web applications that switch single click to double click. This differs from common usability rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Antoine Hegeman gave a good example of UWV website. The online form is accessible, but to finish it, you have to print, sign and mail it the old fashion way. To fix this UWV could start to use DigiD, but why don&#39;t they?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Splash pages (example www.nettorama.nl) is pretty awful too. Every click is a lot of work for someone with cerebral palsy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting to Responsive Design</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/adapting-responsive-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/adapting-responsive-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#34;Responsive design is the red pill from the Matrix. We&#39;ve been living in a conceptual hallucination of control. While &#39;pixel perfect&#39; is the blue pill.&#34; In the early years we used DTP for setting up the boundaries of Web pages. It is something we knew how it works, something we hold on to. We didn&#39;t really know how to handle the internet. Fixed width and height and it should look exact the same as the print. &#34;Reality simply doesn&#39;t work that way.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The media is in all sizes. Big wide monitors, smartphones, tablets, internet via television. There are numbers of screen resolutions out there. It is all fluid. And most important, web page is about content. Web design is about creating solutions how to serve the content on all these devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we go for responsive design: layout that resizes and where content is reordered to fit different screen resolutions. As Mark Boulton has put it: &#34;Responsive design is for us like tumbling down the rabbit hole. Because how do we do responsive design?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Responsive design challenges&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It challenge Business:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It costs more, according to a Disney survey.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The costs lies with the agency doing the work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;People don&#39;t want to pay for it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;So you charge more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use the waterfall approach for responsive design, you&#39;ll find out it is too time and money consuming:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The designer creates a beautiful design in Photoshop (or other design software) for different screen resolutions, the client accepts it or want to have some tweaks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When the design is finished it goes to the front end developer and or programmer. They build it and the website is placed on the server, ready for the content.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The content editor sees the site for the first time and start filling it with content.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Site is ready for launch.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Problem of this approach is how many screen resolutions must the designer take into account in his design mock up? 3 types, like desktop (1024x 786), 1 tablet (600x 800), 1 smartphone: 320 x 480? or 8?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;How many pages must be presented in these mock ups? Homepage? Product page?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;It cannot be pixel perfect. What you see in the mock up can hardly be implemented the exact same way on all screen resolutions, or browsers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;In many cases the content editor has only seen some mock ups and start fill in content when the site is ready. However when the editor starts writing the content he can run into some boundaries of the layout/functionality of the site. In that case the editor can do 2 things: either has to change the content so it fits the design or go back to the designer + development team to let them come with a solution that fits the content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Responsive design challenge Advertising:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Advertising has been ruining the design of content web sites for 20 years.&#34; - Peter-Paul Koch. &#34;Advertisments are really tied to certain sizes. Technically it would be trivial to develop something that would serve different ads at different breakpoints. The advertising model is still selling areas with ads like 50 years ago. In responsive there are no fixed areas.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do we deal with this in responsive designs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advertising don&#39;t want to change. We shouldn&#39;t try to. Just try to make them come to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Responsive design challenges content:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stories have a collections of little pieces of content attached (video, quotes, images, text, etc) The story is no longer a page but a content editor still thinks this way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;a page&#34; doesn&#39;t exist anymore in responsive design. It&#39;s about chunks of content put together in a smart way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive design forces you to focus on the content!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NASA&#39;s job is to inspire a generation. How do you make content more interesting? Try to find anything that would appeal to your mom ;) Create a comphrension matrix on what people might understand (scientists want data not pretty pictures, general public wants the exact opposite). Mark Boulton also talks about work at Cern. If it takes 6 months to generate a homepage image. Do it! People want to see it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not every screen has to show all content: watch Karen McGrane&#39;s video about: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CGyBrlCKySk&#34;&gt;&#34;Adapting to Adaptive Content&#34;&lt;/a&gt; So how should we handle Responsive design? Main point is responsive design affects:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;build process,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;way of working in teams, content and design.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Boultons advice is to let the departments work more closely together. Don&#39;t stay on your island.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A cheap and easy way to work is using pen and paper to create sketches. Some of the customers will freak out, because they expect a fancy design. But in the long run clients will go like &#34;WOW, this works on all devices&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also says that prototyping is the best way. [Personal note to myself: I couldn&#39;t really figure out in the presentation why he believes this is the best way to do responsive design development. But it is something worth to check out.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;And what about CMS?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can we change CMS to make it more natural to work with/display content? CMS need to be more aligned to responsive design principles and let writers be able to structure their content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make your content (text, images etc) reusable instead of just thinking in fixed pages. This is hard, but absolutely neccesary for responsive to work!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further more we need better tools to support the editorial process. Content management is not a technical problem, but a people/process problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style guides are the new Photoshop</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/styleguides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/styleguides/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked Stephen&#39;s chapter in Smashing book #3, so I was really looking forward to see this presentation. Stephen&#39;s presentation is about changing the process of building and designing systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His first advise is to manage clients expectations by designing in the browser instead of creating a static design in Photoshop. This way the customer learns to live with constraints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The disadvantages of Photoshop&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the disadvantages of Photoshop, according to Stephen Hay?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Responsive design implies multiple and flexible layouts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is too much manual work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;And it makes the image editor as a dependency.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Design changes are therefore time consuming.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The advantages of Web technology&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is very practical for responsive design mockups&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making mockups in web tech gives a realistic presentation. Which also helps to manage the clients expectations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is free and open: everyone has a browser&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;editor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No negative surprises for the client&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Possible preperation for development&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;And they can be responsive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Stephen: &amp;ldquo;What is it with designers that they are scared for the command line?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;Audience: &amp;ldquo;It&#39;s not natural. No GUI!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;Stephen: &amp;ldquo;Photoshop is pretty difficult too, for something like the LAB colorspace there are books of &amp;gt; 600 pages!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need two things to replace Photoshop for mock ups. Number one, consider Photoshop not as a design tool for a complete mock up. Number two, use style guides.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The advantages of style guides&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No measuring, with looking at Photoshop and doing math for width etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;State and breakpoint changes can be included.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Useful for future designers, developers&lt;xsl:text&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/xsl:text&gt;others.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Design consistency and maintainability.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;See for some examples of style guides written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gimmebar.com/collection/4ecd439c2f0aaad734000022/front-end-styleguides&#34;&gt;Anna Debenham&lt;/a&gt;. And the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/gel&#34;&gt;BBC GEL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What tools do you need for style guides?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hay has a wish list for the style guide approach:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It should be free-form writable&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Taking screenshots should be automated&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update code snippets automatically&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Automatically update screenshots after change&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elements/modules should not have to be physically split into separate files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Syntax highlight&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are tools available on the internet which can fullfill these wishes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dexy.it&#34;&gt;Dexy&lt;/a&gt;, which you can use for free-form documentation. It is the most flexible documentation tool ever.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://phantomjs.org/&#34;&gt;Phantomjs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://casperjs.org&#34;&gt;Casperjs&lt;/a&gt; for updating screenshots.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jinja.pocoo.org/docs&#34;&gt;Jinja&lt;/a&gt;. For code snippets. It is also a full featured template engine for Python.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pygments.org/&#34;&gt;Pygments&lt;/a&gt; for syntax highlight. The &#34;scary&#34; part is that it involves the command line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also states that the command line is not a scary thing. Photoshop is the most difficult and extensive program. A few command lines shouldn&#39;t be so hard to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Steps for using style guides&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create web based mock up:&lt;br&gt;Your goal is not to create production code when creating a web based mock up. The goal is to represent the design in the browser. Your CSS should be modular because it will end up in your style guide.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;set up style guide:&lt;br&gt;Install dexy, phantom js, caspar js&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write your guide and use jinja templates.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All the CSS for your site should be modular, e.g. using a technique like &lt;a href=&#34;http://smacss.com/&#34;&gt;SMACSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mark the css you want to export&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run Dexy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;ldquo;We design websites, not pictures of websites.&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;- Stephen Hay&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;From my personal view, it is a whole different approach for the designing and development process. I have experience with the eXtreme Programming method for building websites and applications. But the design has always been delivered in Photoshop. I think it will take time to use this approach and to make the work/process going smooth. But that is normal when learning new methods. I&#39;m really interested in other people who use this approach and what they think of it, and most of all how the clients react. Does this approach suits every customer?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New And Improved Developer Toolbelt</title>
      <link>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/developer-toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mirellavanteulingen.nl/conf_2012/developer-toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Addy Osmani showed us a lot of interesting tools which will help developers to build fast and great applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First he explains that tools must change if they can&#39;t evolve.You should also choose your tools well. The less time you can spend on repetitive tasks the more time you can spend on development. This also means that you have to ask yourself once in a while, if the tools you use are the best there are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tooling workflow for developers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make your shell sexy (e.g., color code your terminal, customize to the max! Addy uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iterm2.com&#34;&gt;Iterm2&lt;/a&gt; (for Mac OS)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use dotfiles &lt;a href=&#34;http://dotfiles.github.com&#34;&gt;http://dotfiles.github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Capture your command line history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aliases are great (win7ie8, win8ie10, ) - Done by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.browserstack.com/&#34;&gt;BrowserStack&lt;/a&gt; (browser testing in the cloud)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Auto completion scripts from Bash it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Zen coding with Emmett (PHP) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;Sublime&lt;/a&gt; text editor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sass debug: &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/sass-inspector/lkofmbmllpgfbnonmnenkiakimpgoamn&#34;&gt;sass inspector&lt;/a&gt; for Chrome, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobify.com/dev/sass-sleuth-debugging-sass-in-webkit-browsers/&#34;&gt;sass sleuth&lt;/a&gt; for webkit browsers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/firesass-for-firebug/&#34;&gt;Firesass&lt;/a&gt; for Firefox,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unit testing your frontend code with &lt;a href=&#34;http://qunitjs.com/&#34;&gt;qunit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://pivotal.github.com/jasmine/&#34;&gt;jasmine&lt;/a&gt; can be done in the browser or headless (on demand or with CI)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tips for testing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/&#34;&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt;, can also update &#39;build failed&#39; messages on Github.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanseddon.github.com/bunyip/&#34;&gt;Bunyip&lt;/a&gt;: helps you run unit tests on multiple browsers in the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yeoman.io&#34;&gt;Yeoman&lt;/a&gt;: is a opiniated set of tools. You should go from idea to rough prototype in 10 min, built on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gruntjs.com/&#34;&gt;Grunt&lt;/a&gt; the most popular build tool. Includes support for modules, abstractions, boilerplates and test/build. Supports live reload as well.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t covered everything of Addy&#39;s presentation. I was more interested how he used Sublime text editor and Yeoman, that I stopped writing down notes. After the conference I first installed Sublime. I normally use Textmate, Because I like its GUI and SVN bundle. But I have to say I really start to like Sublime. You can find more notes about Addy Osmani&#39;s presentation on: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hay/fronteers/tree/master/2012/notes&#34; class=&#34;external-link&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hay/fronteers/tree/master/2012/notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>